lbschools.net 2019-06-23

# LBUSD - Long Beach Unified School District: Privacy Statement

Long Beach Unified School District is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Long Beach Unified School District website and governs data collection and usage. By using the Long Beach Unified School District website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

### Collection of your Personal Information

Long Beach Unified School District may collect personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Long Beach Unified School District also may collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Long Beach Unified School District. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by Long Beach Unified School District for the operation of the website, to maintain quality of the website, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Long Beach Unified School District website.

Note: Long Beach Unified School District does not read any of your private online communications.

Long Beach Unified School District encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Long Beach Unified School District so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Long Beach Unified School District is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Long Beach Unified School District and Long Beach Unified School District family of websites.

### Use of your Personal Information

Long Beach Unified School District collects and uses your personal information to operate the Long Beach Unified School District website and deliver the services you have requested. Long Beach Unified School District also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Long Beach Unified School District and its affiliates. Long Beach Unified School District may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Long Beach Unified School District does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Long Beach Unified School District may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (email, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Long Beach Unified School District may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Long Beach Unified School District, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Long Beach Unified School District keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within Long Beach Unified School District, in order to determine what Long Beach Unified School District services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content within Long Beach Unified School District to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Long Beach Unified School District websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Long Beach Unified School District or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Long Beach Unified School District; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Long Beach Unified School District, or the public.

### Use of Cookies

The Long Beach Unified School District website use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Long Beach Unified School District pages, or register with Long Beach Unified School District site or services, a cookie helps Long Beach Unified School District to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Long Beach Unified School District website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Long Beach Unified School District features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Long Beach Unified School District services or Web sites you visit.

### Security of your Personal Information

Long Beach Unified School District secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Long Beach Unified School District secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Changes to this Statement

Long Beach Unified School District will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Long Beach Unified School District encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Long Beach Unified School District is protecting your information.

### Contact Information

If you believe that Long Beach Unified School District has not adhered to this Statement, please send an [email to the webmaster](mailto:webmaster@lbschools.net?subject=LBUSD%20Privacy%20Statement%20Inquiry) at Long Beach Unified School District. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. 

* * *
